Aniket Pradhan

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER

🛮 +91 98975 00297 | 💌 aniketpradhan1999@gmail.com | 🥻 aniket-pradhan.github.io | 🖸 github.com/Aniket-Pradhan | 🛅 linkedin.com/in/ap9989

Personal Profile

A nerd working at Adobe, as a Software Development Engineer. Currently working on the Streaming workflows in the Adobe Experience Platform, to segment billions of different "profiles" within minutes. Zealous about Research and Development, with a few publications at major conferences around Optical Network Communication. Fascinated by Machine Learning and Data Engineering roles.

Work Experience _____

Adobe Noida, India

Computer Scientist - 1 July 2024 - Present

- Collaborated with teams across geographies in the development of Apache Spark and Delta-based big-data architectures, ensuring seamless data updates and performance optimization.
- Implemented a structured approach for internal micro-services, enhancing data accessibility and robustness within Adobe Experience Platform.
 This initiative supports critical functionalities including Segmentation, Profile Export, and Adobe Journey Optimizer.
- Technical Skills: Scala, Apache Spark, DeltaLake, Databricks

Adobe Noida, India

Member of Technical Staff - 2 Feb 2023 - June 2024

- Engaged in cross-functional collaboration to ensure the effective operation and enhancement of the segmentation process, thereby preserving the idempotence of multiple services.
- Enhanced the operational excellence of our owned services, consequently bolstering service stability and diminishing points of failure.
- Facilitated interaction with various teams to secure the timely delivery of novel and refined features, thereby augmenting the criticality of the service
- Technical Skills: Scala, Apache Kafka, Apache Spark, Microsoft Azure, gRPC

Adobe Noida, India

Member of Technical Staff

Jul 2021 - Feb 2023

- At Adobe, I am a part of the Unified Profile Services team, within the Adobe Experience Platform, where I work on the <u>Streaming Segmentation</u> and Edge Segmentation workflows.
- The work revolves around providing real-time segmentation for billions of user profiles around the world with minimal latency as low as in milliseconds.
- Dedicated efforts towards cost optimization for a sub-service, which resulted in a significant annual cost reduction exceeding \$1 million in total.
- Technical Skills: Scala, Apache Kafka, Apache Spark, Microsoft Azure, gRPC

Adobe Noida, India

Product Intern May 2020 - July 2020

- As a Product Intern, I worked on a closed domain question and answering (QnA) framework, using the state-of-the-art methods of natural language processing.
- The QnA framework was designed to be flexible and modular, suitable for Adobe Experience Platform's Documentation.
- Technical Skills: Python with Tensorflow and PyTorch XLA (for Google TPU), Git.

RealVol New Delhi, India

UI Designer Intern

May 2018 – July 2018

- At RealVol I worked on the design and the UI for the product, RealVol
- Technical Skills: Unity VR, C#, Git.

AUGUST 24, 2024

Noida, India

Android Developer Intern June 2018 – July 2018

- Created and implemented simple animations for Android.
- Implemented scalable widgets for Android Applications.
- Technical Skills: Android Studio, Java, Kotlin

Education

Indraprastha Institute of Information Technology - Delhi

Delhi, India

B. Tech in Electronics and Communications Engineering

Aug 2017 - May 2021

· Courses: Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Speech Recognition and Understanding, Game Design and Development, Software Development using Open Source, Digital Audio, Digital Image Recognition

Father Agnel School Delhi, India

2015 - 2017 High School

- Passed with Distinction
- Specialised in Physics, Chemistry, and Maths with Computer Science

Publications

- T. Ahmed, S. Rahman, A. Pradhan et al, "C to C+L Bands Upgrade with Resource Re-provisioning in Optical Backbone Networks", 2021 Optical Fiber Communications Conference and Exhibition (OFC), 2021, pp. 1-3.
- R K. Jana, A. Mitra, A. Pradhan et al, "When Multiband Elastic Optical Networks Becomes More Economical Than Multifiber Elastic Optical Networks?", European Conference on Optical Communication 2020, DOI: 10.1109/ECOC48923.2020.9333276
- A. Mitra, D. Semrau, N. Gahlawat, A. Pradhan et al, "Capacity Benefits of Operation Over C+L Band Elastic Optical Network in the Indian Network Scenario", IEEE ANTS 2019, DOI: 10.1109/ANTS47819.2019.9117992

University Projects _____

Efficient Filling of C+L Bands for an Optical Network

Delhi, India

Indraprastha Insitute of Information Technology - Delhi and British Telecom

May 2019 - May 2020

- Studied the non-linear effects faced by optical signals in a multi-hop path.
- Analyzed link margins in an optical network and studied the methods to reduce them in a backbone optical network.
- Compared the benefits offered by a multi-fiber optical network and a multi-band optical network.
- Technical Skills: Python, LaTeX.

Deep Neural Network Based Predictions of Protein Interactions using Primary Sequences

Delhi, India

Indraprastha Institute of Information Technology - Delhi

Oct. 2018 - Feb. 2019

- · Created a tool in Python to automate data collection and organize the data in a pretty SQL table.
- · Worked on and implemented Deep Structured Semantic Network (DSSM) in Python using Tensorflow
- · Worked on an approach to simplify querying of similarity based protein sequences, using supervised methods
- Technical Skills: Python with Tensorflow, SQL.

AUGUST 24, 2024

IoT Smart Lock Delhi, India

Indraprastha Institute of Information Technology - Delhi

- Dec. 2017 Apr. 2018
- Provides a key less access to the lock with a robust and modular tech stack.
- Secure communications between the clients and the host using TLS 1.2

• Automated lock which can be controlled securely via the Internet.

• Technical Skills: C, Python, Arduino.

Posters_

• A. Sinha, A. Pradhan, Q. Fang et al, "Comp-NeuroFedora, a Free/Open Source operating system for computational neuroscience: download, install, research", Org. for Computational Neurosciences 2020

Skills

Programming Java, Scala, Python (Tensorflow, PyTorch, NumPy, Pandas etc.), C/C++, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, SQL.

Miscellaneous Linux, Shell (Bash/Zsh), Apache Kafka, Apache Spark, Apache Flink, MFX, Git.

Ownership, Time Management, Teamwork, Problem-solving, Documentation, Engaging Presentation, Report writing, Product **Soft Skills**

Design, Logical Thinking

Positions of Responsibilty _____

2020	Byld Admin,	Indraprastha I	nstitute of	Information	Technology - Delhi
------	-------------	----------------	-------------	-------------	--------------------

- 2019 Web Admin, Summer Camp @ Indraprastha Institute of Information Technology - Delhi
- 2019 Volunteer, Summer Camp @ Indraprastha Institute of Information Technology - Delhi
- 2018 Web Admin, Research Showcase @ Indraprastha Institute of Information Technology - Delhi
- Event Head, Student Breakthrough, Research Showcase @ Indraprastha Institute of Information 2018
- Technology Delhi
- 2018 **Event Head**, RoboWars, ESYA @ Indraprastha Institute of Information Technology - Delhi

Languages _____

English Professional proficiency Hindi Native proficiency

French Bilingual proficiency

AUGUST 24, 2024